Karl Roush

karlroush.com • US Citizen karl.roush@gmail.com



Overview

BS/MS Aerospace Engineering graduating with Highest Honors in 3 years; research experience with jet engines, drones, & hands-on shop fabrication. Current work in hypersonics, smart airports, space based ISR, & aircraft emissions. Interests + learning in MBSE, QE, ML/AI, and information security.

Education

Aug 2020 - Dec 2021

Georgia Institute of Technology, MS Aerospace Engineering

BS/MS AE Honors program GPA: 4.00 Propulsion focus

Aug 2017 – May 2020

Georgia Institute of Technology, BS Aerospace Engineering

Summer 2018 Oxford Program, ΣΓΤ Honor society Graduated with Highest Honors (GPA= 3.80)

Experience

Graduate Research Assistant

May 2020 - Present

Aerospace Systems Design Lab

- -Previously Fabrication Lead (Aug 2018-20) under AFRL's Aerospace Propulsion Outreach Program
- -Work including increasing the thrust/weight ratio of a small gas turbine engine by 13.67%, windmill prevention

UTSR Gas Turbine Industrial Fellowship

May 2019 - Aug 2019

Southwest Research Institute: Department of Energy, Office of Fossil Energy

- -Determined viability of hybrid cycle UAVs for surveillance missions & created an NPSS tool for subsequent mission analysis
- -Designed and built laser PIV system for <10% of quoted industry cost for low speed turbulence testing
- -Standardized NPSS unit conversions for international use, streamlined data collection of drag testing (65% time reduction)

Competitive Innovation Consultant

May 2017 - Present

MindSumo: A competitive problem-solving platform; Awarded wins from AAA, Mozilla, NASA, Siemens, GSK, et. al

-Ranked in the top 5 of 350,000+ solvers, Chosen as a winner for 93% of competitions (Mindsumo All-Star average= 20%)

Projects

Jet Engine Cycle Analysis & Optimization

Jan. 2020- May 2020

Off-design cycle design & analysis of a separate flow turbofan in NPSS; Optimized engine for range in a scaled Boeing 737-800

Natural Language Processing Semantris Solver

July 2020

Built a solver for the Google experiment Semantris using Computer Vision + NLP model built from Google News data

Notable Awards/Certificates

Wells Fargo Campus Analytics Challenge Winner (Two Times)

Dec 2018, 2019

Machine learning analytics challenge, 2018= model for minimizing carbon footprint, 2019= Topic generation based on NASA datasets

Eagle Scout Rank Award, Bronze Palm and Gold Palm

Mar 2015

Awarded Bronze Palm in October 2015, Gold Palm September 2016

International Best Use of Data- NASA Space Apps Hackathon

Sept 2016

First Place Overall (Project: EvaS)- Space Apps Next Gen NYC Hackathon Challenge

Developed a search for Extra-Vehicular Activities via NASA's public data in HTML/CSS and JavaScript over the course of ~14 hours

Skills and Certifications

Programs: NPSS, SolidWorks, MATLAB, Git

Languages: Python, C++, HTML/CSS, JavaScript

Machine shop certified

Mill, lathe, band saw, drill press, sanders

Class 4 Laser Safety Certified Laser and Lab Safety Training

German, Latin
ILR Level 2 fluency

Clubs and Activities

American Institute of Aeronautics & Astronautics

GreyHat, Information Security

GT Hytech Racing (FSAE)

Chair, GT Student Chapter

Vice President

Aero/Composites sub-team

Relevant Coursework

Propulsion System Design

Adv. Aircraft Propulsion Optimization Algorithms

Aircraft Design

Flight Dynamics & Controls

Personal Interests

Rapid Prototyping

Metal work & painting

Information security

Machine learning

Service via Eagles@GT